Guide to the William Hillman Shockley Photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909 RL.01177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Korea, 1902, May-August
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1429.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1429.1
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1429.3)
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1430.1)
    Close up of two boats loaded with people, heading to harbor
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1430.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1430.1
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1430.3)
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1431.1)
    Distant view of harbor
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1431.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1431.1
  - Chemulpo, Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1431.3)
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1432.1)
    Walter Townsend and Japanese wife
    Walter D. Townsend was an American businessman living in Korea. He had a son with a Japanese mistress, who died sometime in the 1890s, then married a Japanese woman and adopted her small daughter, who appears in these images. He died in 1918 and is buried in the Foreigners' Cemetery in Incheon, Korea (Chemulpo in Shockley's captions).
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1432.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1432.1
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1432.3)
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1433.1)
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1433.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1433.1
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1433.3)
  - Chemulpo / Adopted daughter of W. D. Townsend, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1434.1)
    Margaret Townsend at about four years of age
  - Chemulpo / Adopted daughter of W. D. Townsend, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1434.2)
    duplocate of RL01177-P-1434.1
  - Chemulpo / Adopted daughter of W. D. Townsend, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1434.3)
    Margaret Townsend, about four years of age
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1435.1)
  - No known title, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1435.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1435.1
  - Korean Lady, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1436.1)
    Interior shot of woman posing with back to camera
  - Korean Lady, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1436.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1436.1
  - Korean Lady, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1436.3)
  - Korean Lady, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1436.4)
  - Main street Seoul, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1437)
  - H.B.M.M. Jordan / Seoul, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1438.1)
    Sir John Newell Jordan, seated in chair
    Sir John Newell Jordan (1852-1925) was an Irish-born British diplomat who became Minister-in-Residence in Seoul, Korea from 1901 to 1905.
  - H.B.M.M. Jordan / Seoul, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1438.2)
    duplicate of RL0177-P-1438.1
  - Palace / Seoul, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1439.1)
    Kyeonghoe-ru pavilion, Gyeongbok Palace
  - Palace / Seoul, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1439.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1439.1
  - Pavilion, Palace Park / Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1440)
    Keunjeong-jon?, royal throne hall, Gyeongbok Palace
  - Seoul / Korea, 1902? (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1441)
  - Family life in Korea, circa 1897 (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1442)
    Children and men on porch of building
  - Fusan / Korea, 1900 (Box 7, Print RL01177-P-1453)
    Ragged children on street
  - Korea, modern copy prints, 1902? (Box 12)
    These 8x10 inch glossy modern copy prints were created from the original glass plate negatives. In the Korea series, they all have corresponding vintage prints.
- Australia, 1901-1902; 122 prints
  During a period roughly from late fall 1901 to May of 1902, Shockley traveled to Australia, chiefly to survey the gold mines of Western Australia, especially near Wiluna. He photographed numerous large and small mining operations with colorful names, many now abandoned; animals and vehicles used in transport, including camels; and workers and overseers, chiefly Europeans. In one image, Shockley stands with R. Atwater, the manager of the Sons of Gwalia Mine, established circa 1896; the construction of this house was commissioned by first mine manager Herbert Hoover, circa 1899. Shockley also photographed several aborigine men and one young woman. His images document the harsh life in these remote regions, and the beginnings of settlements in the Australian outback. On the back of one print he narrates the discovery of a man who nearly died of thirst in the bush but was discovered by Shockley's party.
  Shockley also traveled to the central and eastern cities of Bendigo, Brisbane and Stanthorpe (Queensland), where he photographed mining company buildings, houses, parks, and waterfronts. There are a few images of Perth as well, and of the Japanese steamer that he seems to have taken to Australia.
  Modern 8x10 prints were produced in the 2000's from the glass plate negatives; they are all copies of original prints in the collection. There is one glass plate negative of a nude aboriginal girl that has no print version.
  - Atwater, Shockley / Gwalia, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1454)
    Standing in front of the manager's house
    R. Atwater was manager of the Sons of Gwalia Mine, established circa 1896. The house was commissioned by first mine manager Herbert Hoover, circa 1899.
  - Euro Mining Camp, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1455.1)
  - Euro, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1455.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1455.1
  - Euro, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1456.1)
    View of mine complex
  - Euro, W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1456.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1456.1
  - Euro, W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1457.1)
  - Euro, W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1457.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1457.1
  - Dry Blowing near Euro, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1458.1)
    Two miners panning soil
  - Dry Blowing near Euro W.A., 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1458.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1458.1
  - Dry Blowing near Euro, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1459.1)
  - Dry Blowing near Euro, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1459.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1459.1
  - Sandstorm at Euro, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1460.1)
  - Dust Storm Euro, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1460.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1460.1
  - M. Year [?] & Castle / East Murchison United, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1461.1)
    Shockley and man in front of large house
  - M. Year [?] & Castle / East Murchison United, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1461.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1461.1
  - Near Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1462.1)
    Wagon next to mining site
  - Near Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1462.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1462.1
  - Near Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1462.3)
  - Near Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1462.4)
  - Near Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1462.5)
  - Ashbury [etc?] at Brilliant Mine / W.A. near Lawler's, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1463.1)
  - Brilliant Mine, Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1463.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1463.1
  - Interior of cave near Lawler's showing pitch deposits / Top, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1464.1)
    Back of print has note indicating orientation of image
  - Interior of cave near Lawler's showing pitch deposits, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1464.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1464.1
  - Camels on road near Lawler's, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1465)
  - Mack cleaning Galahi / Corktree Flat W. A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1466.1)
    A galah is a bird of Australia, also known as the rose-breasted cockatoo.
  - Mack cleaning Galahi / Corktree Flat W. A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1466.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1466.1
  - Corktree Flat (Oasis) / Castle lying down, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1467.1)
  - Corktree Flat (Oasis) / Castle lying down, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1467.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1467.1
  - Corktree Flat (Oasis) / Castle lying down, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1467.3)
  - Caves Near Lawler's / W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1468.1)
  - Caves Near Lawler's, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1468.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1468.1
  - Caves near Can Tell / Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1469.1)
  - Caves near Can Tell / Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1469.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1469.1
  - Caves near Can Tell / Lawler's W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1469.3)
  - Never Cantell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1470.1)
  - Never Cantell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1470.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1470.1
  - Never Can Tell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1471.1)
  - Never Can Tell Mine / Lawler's, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1471.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1471.1
  - Spence Arnold / Never CanTell Mine, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1472.1)
  - Spence Arnold / Never CanTell Mine, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1472.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1472.1
  - Never Can Tell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1473.1)
    Wagon with four men next to mine camp
  - Never Can Tell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1473.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1473.1
  - Never Can Tell / W.A. Lawler's, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1474.1)
    Treeless expanse
  - Never Can Tell, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1474.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1474.1
  - Lake Violet, Dec. 1901 / W.A., 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1475.1)
  - Lake Violet, Dec. 1901 / W.A., 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1475.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1475.1
  - Lake Violet, Dec. 1901 / French [?] Williams, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1476.1)
    French-Williams is mentioned in the Mining Magazine, 1914.
  - Lake Violet, Dec. 1901 / French [?] Williams, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1476.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1476.1
  - Lake Violet W.A. / Dec. 1901 / (Black Swan), 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1477)
    Shockley appears on left.
  - Load of Machinery for Lake Violet, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1478.1)
    Camel teams drawing two wagons
  - Load of Machinery for Lake Violet, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1478.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1478.1
  - Building Mill, Lake Violet / W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1479.1)
  - Building Mill, Lake Violet / W.A., circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1479.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1479.1
  - Dec. 1901 / Lake Violet W.A., 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1480.1)
  - Dec. 1901 / Lake Violet, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1480.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1480.1
  - Garden at Lake Way, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1481.1)
  - Lake Way Wiluna, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1481.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1481.1
  - Castle & Tea Trees / near Wiluna, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1482.1)
    Shockley posing next to very large trees
    May refer to Castle Hill Mine.
  - Castle & Tea Trees / near Wiluna, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1482.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1482.1
  - Near Wiluna, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1483.1)
    Distant view through bushes of wagon with team of four horses
  - Near Wiluna, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1483.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1483.1
  - W.A., Chas. Murphy, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1484.1)
    Man in two-wheeled wagon in tall eucalyptus grove
  - W.A., Chas. Murphy, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1484.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1484.1
  - Wiluna, Black fellows, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1485.1)
    Two naked aboriginal men, back view
  - Lake Way, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1485.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1485.1
  - No known title, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1486.1)
    Two naked aboriginal men, front view
  - No known title, 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1486.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1486.1
  - Between Mt. Malcolm, Leonora, 1901 December 27 (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1487.1)
    Weatherbeaten man sitting under small trees
    May be man who was "dying of thirst" in photo group 1488.
  - Between Mt. Malcolm, Leonora, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1487.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1487.1
  - Between Mt. Malcolm, Leonora, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1487.3)
  - Between Mt. Malcolm, Leonora, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1487.4)
  - Between Mt. Malcolm, Leonora, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1487.5)
  - Mulga scrub / Lost man in bush, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.1)
  - Western Australia / Man Dying from thirst / rescued him, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1488.1
  - Mulga scrub / Lost man in bush, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.3)
  - Mulga scrub / Lost man in bush, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.4)
  - Mulga scrub / Lost man in bush, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.5)
  - Mulga scrub / Lost man in bush, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.6)
  - Western Australia, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1488.7)
  - Burning spinifex, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1489)
    Spinifex is a native grass.
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1490)
    Stagecoach to the right of a building
  - W.A., 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1491)
    One-story tin-sided building, "Wildarra Hotel," with wagon and four-horse team standing in front, with Shockley and other men
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1492.1)
    Man, woman, and three children under arbor
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1492.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1492.1
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1493.1)
    Frame dwelling with chimney in front of trees
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1493.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1493.1
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1979.1)
    Another view of frame dwelling with chimney in front of trees
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1979.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1979.1
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1979.3)
  - No known title, circa 1901 December (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1979.4)
  - Murphy's W. A., 1902 March? (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1494.1)
    Distant view of settlement through trees
  - Murphy's W. A., 1902 March? (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1494.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1494.1
  - Near Balbarrack [Balbarupp?] / W.A. Chas. [?] Murphy, 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1495.1)
    May be same man who appears in image 1492.
  - Near Balbarrack [Balbarupp?] / W.A. Chas. [?] Murphy, 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1495.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1495.1
  - Near Balbarrack [Balbarupp?] / W.A. Chas. [?] Murphy, 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1495.3)
  - Near Balbarrack [Balbarupp?] / W.A. Chas. [?] Murphy, 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1495.4)
  - Greenbushes W.A., 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1496.1)
  - Greenbushes W.A., 1902 March (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1496.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1496.1
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1497)
    Large frame house with very tall tree over it; trolley tracks in street
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1498)
    View of city (Bendigo?)
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1499)
    Grove of large eucalyptus (?) and other trees
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1500)
    View of Bendigo; in foreground, Hustler's Royal Reserve Gold Mining Company buildings
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1501.1)
    View of Bendigo with distant steeple of St. John's Presbyterian Church; in foreground, Hustler's Royal Reserve Gold Mining Company buildings
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1501.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1501.1
  - Stanthorpe, Queensland, 1902 April 1 (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1502)
    View of city from other side of Severn River
  - Stanthorpe, Queensland / Chromatic Plate, circa 1902 April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1503)
    Massive boulder
  - Stanthorpe, Queensland, circa 1902 April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1504)
    Boulder field
  - Stanthorpe, Queensland / Chromatic Plate, circa 1902 April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1505)
    View of hills with granite outcrop (?)
  - Stanthorpe, Queensland, 1902 April 1 (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1506)
    Part of town and boulder field
  - Brisbane Park, 1902 March-April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1507)
  - Brisbane, 1902 March-April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1508)
    Hawk at zoological park?
  - Brisbane, 1902 March-April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1509.1)
    View of Brisbane River or Moreton Bay?
  - Brisbane, 1902 March-April (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1509.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1509.1
  - Kasuga Maru, Bath, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1511.1)
    Men on ship deck, taking bath in canvas pool
    The Kasuga Maru was a Japanese mail steamer that took on private passengers.
  - Kasuga Maru, Bath, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1511.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1511.1
  - Kasuga Maru, Bath, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1090.1)
  - Kasuga Maru, Bath, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1090.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1091.1
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1513)
    Two men in arid rocky landscape, pouring water over rock sample
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1514)
    Two small blonde children on large horse with arid landscape behind
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1154.01)
    Houses behind a fence on street
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Box 8, Print RL01177-P-1154.02)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1154.1
  - No known title, 1901 November-1902 May (Print RL01177-GP-001)
    Australian aborigine young female, pregnant?, semi-nude, frontal view
    Unique image; printed format is not in collection.
  - Australia, modern copy prints, 1901-1902, 2 folders (Box 12)
    These 8x10 inch glossy modern copy prints were created from the original glass plate negatives. In the Australia series, they all have corresponding vintage prints.
- Russia: Siberia, 1900; 90 prints
  Locations for these images come from Vladivostok, from which Shockley sailed on the steamer "Progress" to Petropavlosk, Gejiga, the Kamchatka Peninsula, and East Cape, Siberia, visiting the remote locations featured in these photographs in order to search for copper, gold and coal deposits. In addition to surveying for gold and coal, he photographed indigenous peoples, thus there are images of individuals and family groups he labeled as Chuchkis, Tungus (Evenks), Nivkhs, and Koryaks and their reindeer herds. Shockley also photographed European settlers in villages and remote outposts; and the crew and captain of the ship "Progress." A fellow adventurer and mining surveyor, Vanderlip, eventually published a book, In Search of a Siberian Klondike, using many of Shockley's images as illustrations; his narrative, some of which coincides with Shockley's itinerary, provides valuable background to the images in the collection.
  - Vladivostock, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1515)
  - No known title, 1900 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1516)
    Vladivostock
  - Vladivostock, 1900 May (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1517)
    Westerner and coachman in two-horse carriage
  - Koreans at Vladivostock?, 1900 Summer (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1518)
    Man with two children
  - Str. [Steamer] "Progress", 1900 Summer (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1519)
  - Petropavlosk, Kamchatka, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1520)
    View of settlement from water
  - Petropavlosk, Kamchatka, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1521)
    Group of children posing
    3
  - Chuckchis "Progress", 1900 June 19-20 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1522)
    Indigenous woman with two older children
    "Progress" is name of ship
  - Str. [Steamer] Corwin near St. Lawrence Island, 1900 June 19 and 20 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1523)
  - Chukchis / S. Progress / St. Lawrence Island, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1524)
    Indigenous group in front of hut
  - Chuckchis on "Progress", 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1525)
    Indigenous man, woman, and child
  - Loozin Ex convict Interpreter / Shoo Fly / Govt. Engineer Yermakoff / Vanderlip / Center native is "Shoo Fly" / was at world's fair in Chicago 1893 / Near Cape Chaplin / N.E. Siberia, 1900 June (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1526)
    Posed group portrait
    Near Bering Sea.
  - Vanderlip trading Brick Tea for Yukola (dried salmon), 1900 Summer (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1527)
  - Capt. Gunderson and Capt. Coffin looking for passage thru ice near St. Lawrence Island, 1900 June 19-20 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1528)
  - Chukchis / Vanderlip, 1900 June 19-20 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1529)
  - Vanderlip and Chukchis / S. Progress, 1900 Summer (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1530.1)
  - Vanderlip and Chukchis / S. Progress, 1900 Summer (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1530.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-1530.1
  - Vanderlip and Chuchchi, 1900 June (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1531)
    Western man with indigenous woman and child, dog
  - Plover Bay / Siberia, 1900 June 27 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1532)
  - Petropavlosk, Kamchatka, 1900 June (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1533)
    View of settlements from water
  - Capt. Gunderson / "Progress", 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1534)
    Man with dog
  - Capt. Gunderson / Vanderlip / on "Progress" / Malafieff / Jermakoff / Smith / Ossipoff?, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1535)
  - Chinese cooks on "Progress", 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1536)
    Three men with cooking utensils: cleaver, ladle, frying pan
  - Chuchchis [sic] / St. Lawrence Island, 1900 June (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1537)
    Two bare-breasted indigenous women and a child next to a Western man in front of native hut
  - Near Cape Chaplin, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1538)
    Three men with a baby next to a man holding dried fish
  - Engineer Yermakoff / Kurutchkin, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1539)
  - Sounding from "Progress", 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1540)
  - Landing near Cape Chaplin, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1541)
    Long boat with many men
  - No known title, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1542)
    Long boat with many men landing near Cape Chaplin
  - Landing at Cape Chaplin Siberia, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1543)
  - Chook-chees / Cape Chaplin, 1900 June or July (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1544)
    Indigenous men in long boats
  - East Cape, 1900 July 13 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1545)
  - Korak / owner of reindeer / 25 m. west of Cape Navarin, 1900 July 04 (Box 8, Print RL-01177-P-1546)
    Indigenous Koryak man posing